【The fate that cannot be liberated】
[해방될 수 없는 운명]
[Episode 5]
[5화]
Be careful not to get anything on your clothes.
옷에 아무것도 묻지 않도록 주의하세요.
These novels are very interesting.
이 소설들은 매우 흥미롭습니다.
I don’t know where He San is
허산이 어디 있는지 모르겠어요
Get them from there.
거기에서 가져 오세요.
Not even a signature.
서명도 아닙니다.
This scholar must have studied the techniques of writing novels.
이 학자는 소설 쓰기 기술을 연구한 것이 틀림없습니다 .
He is very good at dividing chapters
챕터 나누는 걸 참 잘해요
and make people
그리고 사람을 만든다
I want to buy the next issue.
다음 호를 사고 싶어요.
The role of Du Yingying
두잉잉 역
Who eats chestnuts every day.
매일 밤을 먹는 사람.
She said eating chestnuts
밤을 먹는다고 하더군요
Can enhance internal strength.
내부 강도를 강화할 수 있습니다.
This is really far-fetched.
이것은 정말 말도 안되는 일입니다.
What else do you want to eat?
또 무엇을 먹고 싶나요?
Jinlin’s pea cake?
진린의 완두콩 케이크?
Or the roast duck from Chaotian Alley?
아니면 Chaotian Alley의 구운 오리?
Your brother is on duty this afternoon
네 남동생은 오늘 오후에 당번이야
I can ask him to bring it to you in the evening.
저녁에 가져다 달라고 부탁하면 돼요 .
Chestnuts are awesome. I like to eat chestnuts.
밤은 굉장합니다. 나는 밤을 먹는 것을 좋아합니다.
Here, giving you some inner strength.
여기, 당신에게 내면의 힘을 줍니다.
Actually,
실제로,
Master Rong is here today.
오늘은 롱 선생님이 오셨습니다.
WHO？
WHO?
Rong Yu, Master Rong.
롱 유, 롱 마스터.
What is he doing here?
그 사람 여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
He's always harping on little things.
그는 항상 작은 일에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
I haven't blamed him for ruining my reputation.
나는 내 평판을 망친 것에 대해 그를 비난하지 않았습니다 .
Ling.
링.
What a girl.
정말 좋은 여자야.
Ling, don't be impulsive.
링, 충동적으로 굴지 마세요.
Master Rong is here to deliver something.
Master Rong이 뭔가를 전달하기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
The day you spent the night at the second house of the Rong family,
롱씨네 둘째 집에서 하룻밤을 보낸 날,
he didn't stay there
그는 거기에 머물지 않았다
He has cleared up the rumors.
그는 소문을 정리했습니다.
The astrology center also announced
점성술 센터도 발표했습니다.
No one is allowed to chat further
누구도 더 이상 채팅할 수 없습니다.
About their young master
그들의 젊은 주인에 대해
And you, Ling.
그리고 너, 링.
Are you sure you heard correctly?
확실히 제대로 들으셨나요?
Does he agree?
그도 동의하나요?
Master Rong is so kind to you.
Master Rong은 당신에게 매우 친절합니다.
I heard your brother say
네 형이 말하는 걸 들었어
That young master Rong
그 젊은 스승 롱
Since you returned to the capital, I have been guarding you silently.
당신이 왕도에 돌아온 이후로 나는 묵묵히 당신을 지키고 있습니다.
I think
제 생각에는
You shouldn't be too hostile
너무 적대적이어서는 안 된다
To Master Rong.
룽 선생님께.
After all, he is that person
결국 그 사람이 바로 그 사람이다
Destined to be with you for life.
평생 동안 당신과 함께 할 운명입니다.
Sister, do you like my brother?
언니, 내 동생 좋아해요?
I? ? ?
나? ? ?
when you two get married
너희 둘이 결혼할 때
Do you love each other?
당신은 서로 사랑합니까?
Marriage is the order of parents and the words of matchmaker.
결혼은 부모의 명령 이고 중매인의 말입니다.
before I marry your brother
내가 네 동생과 결혼하기 전에
We only met a few times.
우리는 단지 몇 번만 만났습니다.
So how can we love each other?
그러면 우리는 어떻게 서로 사랑할 수 있습니까?
Didn't think you were? ? ?
당신이 그럴 거라고 생각하지 않았나요? ? ?
Chenzhou and I are in love now.
Chenzhou와 나는 지금 사랑에 빠졌습니다.
I know some people
나는 몇몇 사람들을 알고 있다
People who fall in love and get married
사랑에 빠져 결혼하는 사람들
And then there are people like your brother and me
그리고 나랑 네 형 같은 사람도 있지
Who gets married first
누가 먼저 결혼하나
And then slowly fall in love
그리고 천천히 사랑에 빠지세요
I can understand your reluctance
나는 당신의 거부감을 이해합니다
And you don't like him. It doesn't matter.
그리고 당신은 그를 좋아하지 않습니다. 그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
But that’s all, Rong
하지만 그게 다야, 롱
Be a good person.
좋은 사람이 되십시오.
You may not like him now
지금은 그 사람을 좋아하지 않을 수도 있어요
But you will slowly fall in love with him.
그러나 당신은 천천히 그와 사랑에 빠지게 될 것입니다.
- do you know? ? ? ? - Sister, let me go.
- 그거 알아요? ? ? ? - 언니, 나 좀 놔줘.
Stop talking about these things.
이런 얘기는 그만하세요.
Alright alright.
알았어 알았어.
hurry up.
서둘러요.
I won't talk about him anymore.
나는 더 이상 그에 대해 이야기하지 않을 것입니다.
In a few days it will be the Chinese Valentine's Day.
며칠 후면 중국의 발렌타인 데이가 됩니다.
There will be a lot of great things to eat and do in the capital.
수도에는 먹고 즐길 수 있는 멋진 일들이 많이 있을 것입니다.
General He, I'm leaving first.
장군님, 제가 먼저 갈게요.
If you behaved slightly better at home,
집에서 조금만 더 잘 행동했다면,
your brother and me
네 동생과 나
Will plead with my father
아버지께 변명할게
This way you are no longer grounded.
이렇게 하면 더 이상 접지되지 않습니다.
Qixi festival.
치시 축제.
Two months later,
두 달 후,
this will be an annual
이것은 연간이 될 것입니다
Chinese Valentine's Day fireworks display.
중국 발렌타인데이 불꽃놀이.
you should wait for me
너는 나를 기다려야 해
The Three Sacred Stones of Beijing.
베이징의 세 가지 신성한 돌.
I will take you to explore the city.
나는 당신을 데리고 도시를 탐험할 것입니다.
You haven't been here before this time in previous years,
당신은 지난 몇 년 동안 이 시간 이전에는 여기에 온 적이 없었습니다.
you do not know
넌 몰라
What a lively fireworks show
정말 생동감 넘치는 불꽃놀이네요
Now in the capital.
이제 수도에 있습니다.
That's not to say.
그런 말은 아닙니다.
I have a date with a sister I met in Shangzhou.
상저우에서 만난 언니와 데이트가 있어요.
Sister, you must help me
언니, 꼭 도와주셔야 해요
And talked to my father for me.
그리고 나를 위해 아버지와 이야기를 나눴습니다.
Instead of reflecting at home,
집에서 반성하기보다는
Do you want to go to the Chinese Valentine's Day?
중국 발렌타인 데이에 가고 싶나요?
See the light show?
빛의 쇼를 보시겠습니까?
I think you want to light a lantern on my grave.
내 무덤에 등불을 밝히고 싶은 것 같아요 .
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
Don't worry, she'll be grounded
걱정하지 마세요. 그녀는 접지될 거예요
No matter who pleads for her.
누가 그녀를 위해 간청하든 상관 없습니다.
I have to let her reflect at home.
나는 그녀가 집에서 반성하도록 해야 한다.
What if I intercede for her?
내가 그녀를 위해 중재하면 어떻게 되나요?
Let Miss He go to the Chinese Valentine's Day.
Miss He를 중국 발렌타인 데이에 보내주세요.
The person she is waiting for
그녀가 기다리고 있는 사람
Maybe there is something to say to her.
어쩌면 그녀에게 할 말이 있을지도 모릅니다.
Then there's a deal.
그러면 거래가 있습니다.
Here we have Rouge and Powder.
루즈와 파우더가 있어요.
This one is bigger and contains more sugar.
이것은 더 크고 설탕이 더 많이 포함되어 있습니다.
Hold on.
기다리다.
Sugar-coated haws.
설탕으로 코팅된 산사나무.
Selling candied haws.
설탕에 절인 산사나무를 판매합니다.
- I want one. - OK.
- 내가 하나를 원하는. - 좋아요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Sugar-coated haws.
설탕으로 코팅된 산사나무.
Sweet and sour candied haws.
달콤하고 신맛이 나는 설탕에 절인 산사나무.
Please bless me with a happy husband
행복한 남편으로 축복해주세요
Growing old together.
함께 늙어가는 것.
I want to know
나는 알고 싶다
You only love me in this life.
당신은 이생에서 나만 사랑합니다.
Please, please.
제발 제발.
I can't help you.
나는 당신을 도울 수 없습니다.
This is a suggestion.
이것은 제안입니다.
If he misbehaves,
그 사람이 나쁜 짓을 하면,
Divorce him and find another one.
그 사람과 이혼하고 다른 사람을 찾으세요.
really weird.
정말 이상해요.
It's you.
당신이에요.
Miss He.
미스 헤.
I? ? ?
나? ? ?
Not from Shangzhou? ? ?
상저우 출신이 아니신가요? ? ?
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
elder sister?
언니?
Shangzhou???
상저우???
Yes, you have also been to Shangzhou.
네, 당신도 상저우(Shangzhou)에 가본 적이 있습니다.
Zhanping and others were also present.
Zhanping 등도 참석했습니다.
May I? ? ?
나는 할 수있다? ? ?
but? ? ? but? ? ?
하지만? ? ? 하지만? ? ?
During the trip to Shangzhou,
상저우 여행 중,
you escort someone
당신은 누군가를 호위합니다
- WHO? ? ? - stop. do not talk.
- WHO? ? ? - 멈추다. 말 하지마.
that's me.
그게 나야.
Do I have to believe you?
내가 당신을 믿어야합니까?
I'm waiting for someone. I don't want to see you.
나는 누군가를 기다리고 있습니다. 나는 당신을보고 싶지 않습니다.
You were afraid that I would be bored, so you told me the story of Mount Wuhua.
당신은 내가 심심할까 두려워서 나에게 우화산 이야기를 들려주었습니다.
Are you afraid I won't like the food here?
내가 여기 음식을 좋아하지 않을까 걱정되시나요?
So you roast game for me every day.
그래서 당신은 매일 나를 위해 게임을 굽습니다.
Are you afraid that I won’t be able to sleep well?
내가 잠을 잘 못 잘까 봐 걱정되시나요?
So you gave me the mosquito repellent coil bag you made.
그래서 직접 만드신 모기퇴치 코일백을 저에게 주셨는데요.
Obviously you are not going to Shangzhou
분명히 당신은 Shangzhou에 가지 않을 것입니다
But you took a detour for me.
하지만 당신은 나를 위해 우회로를 택했습니다.
You also tell me
너도 나한테 말해봐
If I come to the capital
내가 수도에 오면
Will you show me around
나한테 주변을 보여 줄래?
And become my best friend.
그리고 나의 가장 친한 친구가 되어주세요.
When I take a shower? ? ?
내가 샤워할 때? ? ?
I smell the Phalaenopsis.
호접란 냄새가 나요.
Miss, are you there?
아가씨, 거기 계세요?
that person
저 사람
It's you?
당신인가요?
sorry.
죄송합니다.
I was very sudden.
나는 매우 갑작스러웠다.
What about menstrual patches?
월경 패치는 어떻습니까?
are you ready?
준비 되었나요?
I have no intention of deceiving you.
나는 당신을 속일 생각이 없습니다.
But I'm on a secret, court-ordered mission
하지만 난 비밀 임무를 수행하고 있어, 법원 명령에 따라
Shangzhou investigates the whereabouts of disaster relief funds
상저우시, 재난 구호 자금 행방 조사
And I can't reveal my identity.
그리고 신원을 밝힐 수도 없습니다.
I don't know which identity I should use
어떤 ID를 사용해야 할지 모르겠습니다.
So I just went along with the mistake.
그래서 나는 그 실수를 그대로 따라갔습니다.
Tell me, is it you?
말해 보세요, 당신인가요?
that's me.
그게 나야.
But I did it privately.
그런데 저는 개인적으로 했어요.
No one else knows about this.
이것에 대해 다른 사람은 아무도 모릅니다.
How, how could you, you? ? ?
어떻게, 어떻게 그럴 수가 있어? ? ?
sorry.
죄송합니다.
I thought you were an elegant gentleman
나는 당신이 우아한 신사라고 생각했어요
But you are a big liar and a scoundrel.
하지만 당신은 대단한 거짓말쟁이이고 악당이에요.
It was my fault.
그것은 내 잘못이었습니다.
I'm just thinking
난 그냥 생각 중이야
Even if I am that person
내가 그 사람이라 해도
Isn’t that enough?
그거면 충분하지 않아?
During the trip to Shangzhou,
상저우 여행 중,
We get along very well.
우리는 아주 잘 지내요.
Can we have? ? ?
우리가 가질 수 있나요? ? ?
But who likes a liar?
그런데 누가 거짓말쟁이를 좋아하겠어요?
don't have any hope
아무 희망도 없어
Stop thinking about me, okay?
내 생각은 그만둬, 알았지?
I think? ? ?
제 생각에는? ? ?
You're angry at the hotel for my rash decision.
당신은 내 성급한 결정 때문에 호텔 측에 화를 냈습니다.
If I go on our date tonight
내가 오늘 밤 데이트를 한다면
You won't be so angry.
당신은 그렇게 화를 내지 않을 것입니다.
I was wrong.
내가 틀렸어.
I misunderstood.
제가 오해했어요.
- This Lantern Festival is so lively. - if you don't like it
- 이번 등불축제는 정말 활기가 넘칩니다. - 마음에 들지 않는다면
I won't be willful
난 고의적이지 않을 거야
like you.
너 같이.
What's the difference?
차이점이 뭐야?
Now the emperor has intervened,
이제 황제가 개입했습니다.
There is no turning back.
되돌릴 수 없습니다.
He Jiuling, don’t be afraid.
He Jiuling, 두려워하지 마십시오.
- Do not be afraid. - How can I not be afraid?
- 두려워 하지마. - 어떻게 두려워하지 않을 수 있습니까?
I will depend on you for the rest of my life
난 평생 당신에게 의지할 거예요
That's the scariest thing.
그게 가장 무서운 일이에요.
Ling.
링.
Senior brother.
선배.
I'm glad you didn't go looking south.
남쪽을 찾지 않아서 다행이에요.
But I'm leaving tonight.
하지만 오늘 밤에 떠날 거예요.
Are you leaving?
너 떠나니?
It's not like we won't meet.
우리가 만나지 않을 것 같지는 않습니다.
wait me back.
기다려 주세요.
Actually, Rong Yu and I? ? ?
사실, 롱유와 나는요? ? ?
- us? ? ? - I do not care.
- 우리를? ? ? - 난 상관 없어.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
I will never let Rong Yu bully me again.
나는 다시는 Rong Yu가 나를 괴롭히는 것을 허용하지 않을 것입니다.
Apart from,
와는 별개로,
These things are difficult to solve, right?
이런 일들은 해결하기 어렵죠?
I'm ready for this.
나는 이것에 대한 준비가되어 있습니다.
I said,
나는 말했다,
I won't let anyone offend you.
누구도 당신을 화나게하지 않을 것입니다.
I am a man of my word.
나는 내 말을 지키는 사람이다.
I thought of a way
나는 방법을 생각했다
This can help you break your engagement with him. are you ready?
이는 그와의 관계를 끊는 데 도움이 될 수 있습니다. 준비 되었나요?
Heshan.
허산.
gentlemen.
신사.
Prepare the horse.
말을 준비하십시오.
I'm going to the palace.
나는 궁전에 갈 것이다.
Yes.
예.
What does this thing mean?
이게 무슨 뜻이에요?
People gather and disperse.
사람들은 모이고 흩어집니다.
Reasons may not necessarily lead to results.
이유가 반드시 결과로 이어지는 것은 아닙니다.
Miss He and I are not a good match.
Miss He와 나는 잘 어울리지 않습니다.
So I went to the emperor
그래서 나는 황제에게 갔다.
And asked for this divorce agreement.
그리고 이번 이혼 합의를 요구했습니다.
From now on, the two of us
지금부터 우리 둘은
Just strangers.
그냥 낯선 사람.
Hope Miss He
그 사람이 그리워요
Another suitable match can be found.
또 다른 적합한 일치 항목을 찾을 수 있습니다.
Do you want to annul your marriage?
결혼을 취소하고 싶나요?
Yes.
예.
But in order to protect Miss He's reputation,
하지만 미쓰헤의 명예를 지키기 위해
divorce letter
이혼 편지
It was written as if General He was the one who initiated the divorce.
마치 그가 이혼을 주도한 사람인 것처럼 쓰여 있었습니다 .
Take it back.
다시 가져.
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
I never told the emperor
나는 황제에게 말한 적이 없다
I want to cancel this marriage
이 결혼을 취소하고 싶어요
I used to think
나는 생각하곤 했어
For people like you, even if you don't like Ling,
당신 같은 사람들은 링을 좋아하지 않더라도
As long as she is your wife
그녀가 당신의 아내인 한
You will always respect and cherish her.
당신은 항상 그녀를 존경하고 소중히 여길 것입니다.
that's why i do
그게 내가 하는 이유야
Entrust her to you.
그녀를 당신에게 맡기세요.
But since the incident
하지만 그 사건 이후로
At the palace banquet,
궁궐 연회에서,
I know how you feel.
나는 당신이 어떻게 느끼는지 알고있다.
So you're here today,
그래서 당신은 오늘 여기에 있습니다.
As her father,
그녀의 아버지로서,
I know why.
나는 이유를 안다.
It doesn't matter how I feel.
내 기분은 중요하지 않습니다.
So you want to annul the marriage
그래서 결혼을 무효로 하려는 거군요
As she wished?
그녀가 원했던 대로?
If a marriage is annulled,
혼인이 취소된 경우,
Then I, He Liang, misjudged you.
그렇다면 나 He Liang은 당신을 잘못 판단했습니다.
Xiaoling is not yet 17 years old.
샤오링은 아직 17세가 되지 않았습니다.
She spent her whole life
그녀는 평생을 보냈습니다
Deal with the poisonous insects and snakes in Wuhua Mountain.
Wuhua Mountain의 독충과 뱀을 처리하세요.
When she returned to the capital,
그녀가 수도로 돌아왔을 때,
I spoiled her into a girl
나는 그녀를 여자로 망쳤다
Who doesn’t understand any rules or etiquette.
어떤 규칙이나 에티켓도 이해하지 못하는 사람.
She doesn't understand what it means
그녀는 그게 무슨 뜻인지 이해하지 못해요
To like or love someone.
누군가를 좋아하거나 사랑하다.
she does not know.
그녀는 모른다.
But I do.
하지만 나는 그렇습니다.
Love is restraint,
사랑은 구속이다.
I'm afraid,
나는 두렵다.
It’s a heart that wants someone to be happy
누군가가 행복했으면 하는 마음이에요
More important than my own happiness.
내 행복보다 더 중요한 것은.
Hope Miss He
그 사람이 그리워요
To meet such a person,
그런 사람을 만나려면
So I want to give her freedom.
그래서 나는 그녀에게 자유를 주고 싶다.
This is also the last thing
이것도 마지막이네요
What can I do for her now?
이제 내가 그녀를 위해 무엇을 할 수 있을까?
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
I won't accept it
나는 그것을 받아들이지 않을 것이다
This divorce agreement.
이번 이혼합의서.
Zong Ming.
종밍.
Send him out.
그를 내보내세요.
starting today,
오늘부터,
Ling will be grounded for half a year.
링은 반년 동안 출장이 금지됩니다.
Who dares to indulge her
누가 감히 그녀를 탐닉하겠는가?
and let her out
그리고 그녀를 내보내줘
It won't be my family.
내 가족은 아닐 거예요.
What did I do again?
내가 또 무슨 짓을 한 거지?
- Dad, me? ? ? - What? Are you not happy?
- 아빠, 나요? ? ? - 무엇? 당신은 행복하지 않습니까?
Dad, let's eat.
아빠, 먹자
Have you forgotten what you said?
당신이 말한 것을 잊었습니까?
Don’t want to get angry at the dinner table?
저녁 식탁에서 화내고 싶지 않으신가요?
I'm not unhappy.
나는 불행하지 않다.
I just heard that Rong Yu is here.
방금 Rong Yu가 여기에 있다는 소식을 들었습니다.
Why do you care?
왜 신경쓰나요?
I'm just asking.
그냥 물어보는 거야
Dad, are you so angry with me now?
아빠, 지금 나한테 그렇게 화났어요?
Why did Rong Yu come here?
유용준이 왜 여기에 왔나요?
Is he here to deliver a betrothal gift?
그 사람이 약혼 선물을 전달하러 왔나요?
Why do you care?
왜 신경쓰나요?
Ling.
링.
your engagement
당신의 약혼
With Rong Yu
유롱과 함께
Will not be cancelled.
취소되지 않습니다.
He loves you more than you can imagine.
그분은 당신이 상상하는 것 이상으로 당신을 사랑하십니다.
It's not easy to find someone
사람찾기가 쉽지 않네요
Who cares about you so much.
누가 당신을 그렇게 많이 걱정합니까?
Don't do stupid things
어리석은 짓은 하지 마세요
Let him down.
그를 실망시키세요.
What if he doesn't care about me anymore?
그 사람이 더 이상 나에게 관심이 없다면 어떡하지?
Can you stop forcing me to marry him?
나한테 그 사람과 결혼하라고 강요하는 걸 그만둘 수 있나요?
He will not.
그는 그렇지 않을 것입니다.
Jiuling maybe
어쩌면 지울링
You should accept your fate.
당신은 당신의 운명을 받아들여야 합니다.
If Rong Yu is bored and doesn't play with you, I will play with you.
용우가 심심해서 너랑 안 놀아주면 내가 너랑 놀아줄게.
Rong Yu doesn’t know martial arts and can’t fight.
용우는 무술을 모르고 싸울 줄도 모릅니다.
But I will fight for you.
하지만 나는 당신을 위해 싸울 것입니다.
If he annoys you, go home.
그 사람이 짜증나면 집에 가세요.
I will always protect you
나는 항상 당신을 보호 할 것입니다
Let you be happy and carefree, okay?
행복하고 평온하게 지내세요. 알았죠?
You're not much older than me.
당신은 나보다 나이가 많지 않습니다.
But you call yourself "brother."
그런데 당신은 스스로를 "형제"라고 부르죠.
You work in the Department of Justice, such a serious place,
당신은 법무부에서 일해요. 정말 심각한 곳이죠.
But why are you more talkative than before?
그런데 왜 아까보다 말이 많아졌나요?
why cry? Come, eat some more.
왜 울어요? 자, 좀 더 먹어보세요.
Come on, Ling, have some more.
어서, 링, 좀 더 드세요.
- She started to cry. - Eat your food.
- 그녀는 울기 시작했어요. - 네 음식을 먹어.
slow down.
천천히 해.
[To Rong Yu]
[유롱에게]
This is a new medicine I formulated last year.
이것은 제가 작년에 개발한 새로운 약입니다.
People who use it will become cold and heartless,
그것을 사용하는 사람들은 차갑고 무정해질 것이며,
No longer able to produce affectionate thoughts
더 이상 애정 어린 생각을 할 수 없습니다
To someone you once liked.
한때 좋아했던 사람에게.
You know Rong Yu likes me.
당신은 Rong Yu가 나를 좋아한다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Loving someone is an evil desire
누군가를 사랑하는 것은 사악한 욕망이다
use all possible means
가능한 모든 수단을 동원하다
Let her stay with you.
그녀가 당신과 함께 있게 해주세요.
Why can't I see it?
왜 볼 수 없나요?
As long as he still likes you
그 사람이 여전히 당신을 좋아하는 한
He won't let go easily.
그는 쉽게 놓아주지 않을 것이다.
Give him this medicine as soon as possible
가능한 한 빨리 그에게 이 약을 주세요
Everything will be solved immediately.
모든 것이 즉시 해결될 것입니다.
He was deeply favored by the emperor,
그는 황제의 총애를 많이 받았고,
So it should be easy for him to break off the engagement.
그러므로 그가 약혼을 파기하는 것은 쉬울 것입니다.
What is the name of this medicine?
이 약의 이름은 무엇입니까?
amnesia.
기억력 상실.
I will use this medicine
나는 이 약을 사용할 것이다
Let him let go.
그를 놓아주세요.
The Crown Princess's father.
왕세녀의 아버지.
Your Highness, are you calling me?
전하, 지금 전화 중이신가요?
Otherwise, do you want me to call you daddy?
그렇지 않으면 내가 당신을 아빠라고 부르길 원하시나요?
This is not impossible.
이것은 불가능하지 않습니다.
I can not.
나는 할 수 없다.
I was confused by the title.
제목이 헷갈렸어요.
You may not know this,
이 사실을 모르실 수도 있는데,
But He Jiuling has already
그러나 He Jiuling은 이미
Give me your daughter as a princess.
당신의 딸을 공주로 보내주세요.
So, you are now the father of the Crown Princess.
그럼 이제 당신은 왕세자비의 아버지가 되셨습니다.
- I? ? ? - The Crown Princess's father.
- 나? ? ? - 왕세녀의 아버지.
You knelt down a few days ago
며칠 전에 무릎을 꿇었잖아
Spent several hours outside my father's study.
아버지 서재 밖에서 몇 시간을 보냈습니다.
Someone secretly brings you water and snacks.
누군가 몰래 물과 간식을 가져다줍니다.
In fact, I arranged this.
사실 제가 이걸 정리했어요.
Thank you, Your Highness.
감사합니다, 전하.
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
By the way, why did you come to the palace again today?
그런데 오늘은 또 왜 궁에 오셨나요?
What do you want to ask about my father?
우리 아버지에 대해 무엇을 묻고 싶나요?
Not solved yet?
아직 해결되지 않았나요?
If anything, I can intercede for you.
무엇이든 내가 당신을 위해 중재할 수 있습니다.
already solved.
이미 해결되었습니다.
Today, I am here to say goodbye to His Majesty.
오늘 저는 폐하께 작별 인사를 하러 이 자리에 왔습니다.
Are you leaving the capital?
수도를 떠나는 건가요?
I plan to go to Hanshan Temple to meditate and practice for a while.
나는 한동안 한산사에 가서 명상하고 수행할 계획이다 .
Do you want to become a monk? This is unacceptable.
스님이 되고 싶나요? 이것은 용납될 수 없습니다.
How about an astrology clinic? Where is He Jiuling?
점성술 스튜디오는 어때요? He Jiuling은 어디에 있습니까?
I have no intention of becoming a monk, but I am just going to visit His Highness.
저는 스님이 될 생각은 없고 단지 폐하를 만나러 갈 뿐입니다.
The Star Pavilion will be looked after by my uncle.
스타 파빌리온은 삼촌이 돌보실 거예요.
He also helps me observe star charts.
그는 또한 내가 별자리를 관찰하도록 도와줍니다.
As for Miss He,
미스히의 경우,
It's not my place to talk about her.
그녀에 대해 이야기하는 것은 내가 할 일이 아닙니다.
in a few days,
며칠 안에,
Your Highness will know.
전하께서는 아실 것입니다.
It's not easy to get her
그녀를 얻는 것은 쉽지 않습니다
from the enemy.
적에게서.
Rong Yu, you should keep her by your side.
Rong Yu, 그녀를 옆에 두어야합니다.
If Your Highness has no other needs
전하에게 다른 필요가 없다면
I'm going to take my leave.
나는 휴가를 떠날 예정이다.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
I can't get out.
나는 나갈 수 없다.
How can I get you to work your magic?
당신이 마법을 부리게 하려면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
dad.
아빠.
Should I? ? ?
내가해야합니까? ? ?
At.
에.
Do you have to go to Hanshan Temple?
한산사에 꼭 가야하나요?
It is full of severe practice.
혹독한 연습이 가득합니다.
Even for the sake of enlightenment,
깨달음을 위해서라도,
You don't have to choose this
굳이 이걸 선택할 필요는 없어
Far away and harsh place, right?
멀고 험난한 곳이죠?
The physical pain doesn't sting at all.
육체적인 고통은 전혀 따갑지 않습니다.
Uncle, send me this box
삼촌, 이 상자 좀 보내주세요
Go to General He's Mansion.
장군님의 저택으로 가세요.
What happened between you and the He family?
당신과 He 가족 사이에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
later,
나중에,
You will know.
넌 알게 될거야.
He Jiuling invited me to her home.
He Jiuling은 나를 그녀의 집으로 초대했습니다.
Get me dressed quickly and pack some gifts.
빨리 옷을 챙겨주고 선물도 챙겨주세요.
Choose some quirky, rare gifts. hurry up.
기발하고 희귀한 선물을 선택하세요. 서둘러요.
- look at this. - Yes.
- 이거 봐요. - 예.
I can't imagine how it could be like this.
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있는지 상상할 수 없습니다.
- We should be extra careful now. - Yes.
- 지금은 특히 조심해야 해요. - 예.
It's Rong Yu's carriage.
그것은 Rong Yu의 마차입니다.
Rong Yu, keep up the good work.
Rong Yu님, 계속 좋은 일을 하세요.
something's up. Go get help.
무슨 일이 생겼어요. 가서 도움을 받으세요.
Your Highness, I'm sorry for not greeting you from afar.
전하, 멀리서 인사드리지 못해 죄송합니다.
Please forgive me.
용서해주세요.
There is no need for this. I'm not here to see you.
그럴 필요가 없습니다. 나는 당신을 만나러 여기 온 것이 아닙니다.
I'm here to play with He Jiuling.
나는 He Jiuling과 놀러 왔습니다.
Jiuling.
지울링.
Jiuling is reading in the backyard.
Jiuling은 뒷마당에서 책을 읽고 있습니다.
Your Highness, Your Highness.
전하, 전하.
I'll let her clean up and come see you.
내가 그녀에게 청소를 맡기고 당신을 만나러 올게요.
- I'll go straight to her. - Your Highness.
- 바로 그 사람한테 갈게요. - 전하.
Stop following me. This is between our children.
따라 다니지 말아 줘. 이건 우리 아이들 사이의 일이에요.
What are the adults doing here?
어른들은 여기서 뭐하는 걸까요?
General He, go and deal with your own affairs.
장군님, 가서 당신의 일을 처리하십시오.
Your Highness, please be careful.
전하, 조심하시기 바랍니다.
He Jiuling, the Crown Princess’s mother.
황태자의 어머니 허구령(佐九陵).
You all stay here. Don't disturb He Jiuling and me.
너희는 모두 여기에 머물러라. He Jiuling과 나를 방해하지 마십시오.
Your Highness, actually I have something to tell you.
전하, 사실 제가 드릴 말씀이 있습니다.
What do you want to say?
말하고 싶은게 뭡니까?
If there is something urgent, His Highness
급한 일이 있으면 전하
Then His Highness should speak first.
그러면 전하께서 먼저 말씀하셔야 합니다.
Of course, I was anxious.
물론 불안했어요.
Your husband is leaving the capital.
당신의 남편이 수도를 떠나고 있습니다.
Did you have a fight?
싸웠나요?
You don't even know about it.
당신은 그것에 대해조차 모릅니다.
Didn't he say goodbye to you?
그 사람이 당신에게 작별 인사를 하지 않았나요?
Then I'll tell you.
그럼 내가 말해주지.
Rong Yu is leaving the capital today.
유용우(Rong Yu)가 오늘 수도를 떠난다.
He is going to Hanshan Temple to meditate
그는 한산사에 가서 명상을 하려고 합니다
And won't be back for several months.
그리고 몇 달 동안 돌아오지 않을 거예요.
A few months?
몇 달?
- It's so long - Yes.
- 너무 길어요 - 네.
How could he be willing to stay?
그가 어떻게 기꺼이 머물 수 있었습니까?
My princess's mother?
우리 공주의 어머니요?
Doesn't he want to take responsibility?
그 사람은 책임을 지고 싶지 않은 걸까?
He avoided me, afraid that I would find him.
그는 내가 그를 찾을까 봐 두려워 나를 피했습니다.
What are you doing with him?
그 사람이랑 뭐하는 거야?
there is nothing. In fact, Your Highness,
아무것도 없습니다. 사실, 전하,
I have a favor to ask you.
부탁드릴 게 있어요.
Instruct the kitchen to prepare
주방에 요리 지시하기
- Some foods that children like. - OK.
- 아이들이 좋아하는 음식들. - 좋아요.
- Especially pastries.
- 특히 패스트리요.
Your Highness.
전하.
Your Highness, you seldom come here,
전하, 이곳에 거의 오시지 않습니다.
I've ordered lunch.
점심을 주문했어요.
Maybe you can leave.
어쩌면 당신은 떠날 수 있습니다.
No need, I haven’t finished the calligraphy homework assigned by my teacher yet.
필요없어요. 선생님이 주신 서예 숙제를 아직 못 끝냈어요.
I have to go back and finish it. let's go.
돌아가서 마무리해야 해요. 갑시다.
What about these boxes?
이 상자들은 어때요?
I brought some things to He Jiuling when I came here.
여기에 왔을 때 He Jiuling에 몇 가지 물건을 가져 왔습니다.
She returned some gifts.
그녀는 몇 가지 선물을 돌려주었습니다.
She didn't tell me this.
그녀는 나에게 이것을 말하지 않았습니다.
Your Highness, you are of noble birth.
전하, 당신은 고귀한 가문 출신입니다.
Jiuling
지우링
Her work is often not detailed enough.
그녀의 작업은 종종 충분히 자세하지 않습니다.
What if she brings up something inappropriate?
그녀가 부적절한 말을 꺼내면 어떻게 되나요?
And accidentally hurt you?
실수로 상처를 입혔다고요?
Then what should I do?
그러면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
maybe i should
아마도 내가 해야 할 것 같아
Take a look.
구경하다.
Nothing to see.
볼 것이 없습니다.
It's nothing, General.
아무것도 아닙니다, 장군님.
Your Highness, after all, this is
전하, 결국 이것은
Things shipped from the General's Mansion.
장군 저택에서 배송된 물건들입니다.
I'm worried? ? ?
걱정되나요? ? ?
unnecessary. I've seen it all.
불필요한. 나는 그것을 모두 보았다.
He Jiuling just gave some common things.
He Jiuling은 몇 가지 공통점을 제시했습니다.
This is even more unacceptable.
이는 더욱 받아들일 수 없는 일이다.
Your Highness, there is something you don't know.
전하, 당신이 모르는 것이 있습니다.
Some things in Jiuling may be very dangerous.
Jiuling의 어떤 것들은 매우 위험할 수 있습니다.
Especially those weird drugs on her body.
특히 그녀의 몸에 있는 그 이상한 약물들.
What if they accidentally hurt you?
실수로 당신에게 상처를 입힌 경우에는 어떻게 합니까?
I would be the culprit.
나는 범인이 될 것입니다.
Please let me check it.
확인해 보시기 바랍니다.
- There's really nothing to check. - Your Highness.
- 실제로 확인할 것은 없습니다. - 전하.
Please let me check it.
확인해 보시기 바랍니다.
There's really nothing to check.
실제로 확인할 것이 없습니다.
It will be quick.
그것은 빠를 것이다.
Where do these bees come from?
이 벌들은 어디서 오는 걸까요?
There are bees.
꿀벌이 있습니다.
Come on, run, run.
어서, 달리고, 달리세요.
What? Leave quickly.
무엇? 빨리 떠나세요.
Sorry, Dad.
미안해요, 아빠.
I'm even more sorry for the prince.
왕자에게는 더욱 미안합니다.
【Ministry of Justice】
【법무부】
Robbery, robbery.
강도, 강도.
What does robbery mean?
강도는 무슨 뜻인가요?
Robbery is the taking of people or money
강도는 사람이나 돈을 빼앗는 행위이다
Got it from the owner in broad daylight.
대낮에 주인에게서 받았습니다.
How is this different from robbery?
이것이 강도와 어떻게 다릅니까?
There are no lethal weapons and no harm will be done to people.
치명적인 무기는 없으며 사람에게 해를 끼치는 일도 없습니다.
What is the difference between this and usurpation?
이것이 강탈과 무엇이 다른가요?
Haven't I explained it?
내가 설명하지 않았나요?
Last case for you?
마지막 사건인가요?
Do you?
당신은?
Report.
보고서.
Outside the city gate, I met Master Cheng Chong.
성문 밖에서 나는 Cheng Chong 스승을 만났습니다.
Fortunately, His Highness was not stung.
다행히 전하는 쏘이지 않았습니다.
- Your hair is a bit messy, though. - What does it matter?
- 그런데 머리가 좀 지저분해요. - 그것은 무슨 상관이야?
You should sort it out later.
나중에 정리해야 합니다.
But you are indeed powerful.
하지만 당신은 정말 강력합니다.
You even manipulated bees.
당신은 심지어 벌을 조작하기도 했습니다.
This is just some lure powder.
이것은 단지 미끼 가루입니다.
Don't use it now. There are a lot of bees and butterflies here
지금은 사용하지 마세요. 이곳에는 벌과 나비가 많이 있어요
In the wilderness.
광야에서.
This can be very dangerous.
이는 매우 위험할 수 있습니다.
The next time you use it,
다음에 사용하게 된다면,
Make sure to protect yourself first.
먼저 자신을 보호하십시오.
return.
반품.
This is used in the palace
궁궐에서 사용하는 것인데
For Miss Jiang of the Hou Mansion.
허우 저택의 장 씨를 위해.
It helps expel gas and enhances body scent.
가스를 배출하고 몸의 향기를 향상시키는 데 도움이 됩니다.
Cool, so cool! Give them all to me.
멋지다, 정말 멋지다! 나에게 모두 주세요.
Your Highness saved me.
전하께서 저를 구해 주셨습니다.
This is just a small thank you.
이것은 단지 작은 감사입니다.
I gotta go. I still have to chase Rong Yu.
난 가야 해. 나는 여전히 Rong Yu를 쫓아야합니다.
【Jiangzhen】
【장전】
Master, it's already five o'clock in the afternoon
선생님 벌써 오후 5시네요
Should we stop for something to eat?
우리 뭐 좀 먹으러 멈춰야 할까?
Master?
주인?
should we have something to eat
우리 뭐 좀 먹을까?
Then find an inn to rest?
그럼 쉴 여관을 찾아볼까?
Tomorrow we can continue our journey.
내일 우리는 여행을 계속할 수 있습니다.
OK
좋아요
Flatten, you can stop.
평평해지면 멈출 수 있습니다.
Master.
주인.
Let's get off the carriage first.
먼저 마차에서 내리자.
???Under the sunset at dusk? ? ?
???해질녘 노을 아래서요? ? ?
???I traveled thousands of miles to a distant place? ? ?
???나는 먼 곳으로 수천 마일을 여행했다고요? ? ?
???Playing the piano under the moonlight? ? ?
???달빛아래 피아노 연주? ? ?
???These drinks won’t make me forget? ? ?
???이 음료수는 잊혀지지 않을까요? ? ?
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
???내가 당신을 위해 쓴 소망은요? ? ?
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있다고? ? ?
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 최강의 와인을 좋아하시나요? ? ?
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 운명을 피할 방법은 없나요? ? ?
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
???뒤돌아보니 기다리고 있는거 보이시죠? ? ?
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
???우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니까? ? ?
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 밝은 은하계로 결정화되기를 원하시나요 ???
???You quietly turned around and closed the marriage certificate? ? ?
??? 조용히 돌아서서 결혼증명서를 닫았나요? ? ?
???Ask how many stars are there in the sky? ? ?
???하늘에 별이 몇 개 있는지 물어보세요. ? ?
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
???내가 당신을 위해 쓴 소망은요? ? ?
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있다고? ? ?
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 최강의 와인을 좋아하시나요? ? ?
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 운명을 피할 방법은 없나요? ? ?
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
???뒤돌아보니 기다리고 있는거 보이시죠? ? ?
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
???우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니까? ? ?
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 밝은 은하계로 결정화되기를 원하시나요 ???
???I gently caress the guzheng, waiting for passers-by like you???
???나는 고젱을 부드럽게 어루만지며 당신같은 행인을 기다린다???
???So you are my indissoluble bond? ? ?
???그럼 당신은 나의 불용성 유대인가요? ? ?